

## Eric Matamoros Senior Data Scientist

**Age:** 23 **Area:** Barcelona **Tel.** +34 654798580

ericmatamoros1999@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/eric-matamoros-morales

https://github.com/ericmatamoros

## **Education**

- · Bachelor in Biochemistry at UB. Final Mark: 8.3
- · Master in Bioinformatics & Biostatistics at UOC Current mark: 8.2

#### Languages

Catalan - Native Spanish - Native English - C1

## **Programming Languages**

Python R SQL

## **Architectures**

Cloud - AWS Jenkins Docker Github

## **Technical Skills**

- · Data Analysis, Cleaning & Visualization
- · Predictive Modelling
- · Problem Solving
- · Pipeline Design
- · Analytical Mindset

## **Soft Skills**

- · Attention to Detail
- · Hard-working
- · Communication
- · Positive environment

## **Profile**

Senior Data Scientist with +3 years of experience in developing datadriven solutions to solve real business problems. I am an ex-entrepreneur, ambitious and hard-working person, enjoying to collaborate with other associates through the creation of a positive environment, where we can fully enjoy our work while delivering high-end products.

From my experience, what I truly like about this profession is the capability to innovate, create & bridge maths & statistics with business.

## **Employment History**

26/06/2020 - Actual
Digital Finance Hub - Novartis Pharma
01/06/2023 - Actuals
Senior Data Scientist at Novartis Pharma



## 27/06/2021 - 1/06/2023

## **Expert Data Scientist at Novartis Pharma**

- · Led numerous workshops and presentations for business stakeholders from the *UK*, *Germany*, *Spain*, *France*, *Italy*, *the US*, *Canada*, *Japan and South American* countries
- Led & constructed an approach to model the impact on the sales due to a transition of the lifecycle moment of a product.
- · Fully migrated a major Novartis project from R to Python
- · Working on a daily basis with multiple programming languages (R, Python, SQL, Git) for the completion of tasks while relying on Agile Methodologies
- · Technical Lead of the Novartis Datathon 2022, an international competition with more than 50 different teams.

## 26/06/2020 - 26/06/2021

## **Trainee Data Scientist at Novartis Pharma**

Involved in the developing of the Baseline algorithm, that predicts the 3-year monthly forecast through the ensemble of multi-/univariate models.



## 15/09/2019 - 27/06/2021

## Computational Biologist at IRB Barcelona

- · RNA tertiary structure prediction through combined ML and Bayesian inference approaches into Monte Carlo simulations. Done in Python.
- · Bayesian inference to develop a scoring function in order toe valuate RNA pseudo-torsional angles. Done in R.

## **Internships**

# School of molecular and theoretical biology

## 2/08/2016 - 18/08/2016

## **Bioinformatician Trainee at SMTB**

Real-time simulations of the folding and refolding of the von Willebrand Factor (vWF) under stenosis conditions. Unfolding of the protein was reported to be related with arterial thrombosis. Done in Python.

Advisor: Dmitry Nechipurenko, Pl



#### 13/06/2016 - 27/06/2016

## **Computational Biologist Trainee at IRB Barcelona**

Developed Monte-Carlo Simulations of chromosome folding in order to study the impact of methylation and de methylation pathways in its folding. Done in Python.

Advisor: Modesto Orozco, PI

## 11/07/2016 - 29/07/2016

#### **Bioinformatician Trainee at CRG**

Involved in the international study "Saca la Lengua", aimed to find a correlation between the microbiome and the habits of students across Spain. Assessed gene expression & homology studies in different samples of study. Done in Python & Bash.

Advisor: Toni Gabaldon, Pl

# Entrepeneurship

09/01/2019 - 18/12/19

## Co-founder at Biop Al Ltd.

Biop Al Ltd. deploys Al solutions for the early-stage cancer diagnosis. In charge of the operations of the company. Closed.

## **Courses and Certifications**

## Machine Learning, Python & R

- · Data Scientist with R Career Track in DataCamp. (22 courses)
- · Machine Learning Scientist with R CareerTrack in DataCamp (15 courses)
- · Data Scientist with Python Career Track in DataCamp (23 courses)
- · Machine Learning Scientist with Python CareerTrack in DataCamp (23 courses)
- · Introduction to Deep Learning DeepLearningI

Credentials: Since it's a bundle, they can be provided upon request of the employer

· Neural Networks and Deep Learning - DeepLearningAl

Credentials: Since it's a bundle, they can be provided upon request of the employer

## Architectures: Kubernetes

- · Data Analyst with SQL Server Career Track in DataCamp (11 courses)
- · Docker and Kubernetes: The Complete Guide Udemy

Credential: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-30278b40-d30c-4ec5-a37e-e32bcd9a041b/

#### Microsoft Excel:

· Microsoft Excel - Data Analysis with Excel and Pivot Tables - Udemy

Credential: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-e1e27c94-1e21-4257-ab20-56093baf1a1c/

· Microsoft Excel - Data Visualization, Excel Charts and Graphs - Udemy

Credential: https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-f37b8f70-de14-41f5-bde3-e9f80b04cf79/